Guide to the Office of Undergraduate Education Records, 1980-2012 UA.07.06.0005
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Office of Undergraduate Education Records
1980-2017
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Office of Undergraduate Education
UA.07.06.0005
1.0 Linear Feet
The Office of Undergraduate Education supports and coordinates the many facets of the undergraduate experience. The Office of Undergraduate Education records include reports, speeches, and reaccreditation materials, among other documents.
Biographical / Historical
The Office of Undergraduate Education supports and coordinates the many facets of the undergraduate experience, with a particular focus on promoting student success in all aspects of Duke life. The office oversees academic advising, financial aid, and programs such as DukeEngage and Faculty in Residence.
Source: Office of Undergraduate Education website, https://undergrad.duke.edu/about, accessed October 02, 2020.
Access Restrictions
Access restricted. Records of the University's Board of Trustees which have been in existence for at least fifty years are available for scholarly research with the permission of the University Archivist. Access to records which have been in existence for less than fifty years shall be granted only by special permission, in writing, from the Board of Trustees. Contact Research Services for more information.
Provenance
The Office of Undergraduate Education records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a transfer in 2018.
Collection Overview
The Office of Undergraduate Education records include reports, speeches, and reaccreditation materials, among other documents.
Conditions Governing Access
Access note. Collection contains electronic records that may need to be reformatted. Access copies of electronic records must be accessed in our reading room. Contact Research Services for access.
Conditions Governing Access
Access restricted. For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use of administrative records. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist. Contact Research Services for more information.
College students -- United States; Duke University. Office of Undergraduate Education; Duke University -- Students; Friedl, Ernestine, 1920-
- Accession UA2018-0049, 1980-2017
  - Compliance Report: Reaffirmation of Accreditation Southern Association of Colleges and Schools Commission of Colleges, 2008-2009; 2 folders (Box 1)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Electronic materials must be reformatted before use.
    Administrative restriction until 2034.
  - The University Plan, 2001 (Box 1)
    Administrative restriction until 2026.
  - Assorted Pamphlets, 2007-2017 (Box 1)
  - Keohane Speech/BOT, 1985-2013 (Box 1)
    Board of Trustees restrictions until 2063.
  - Reports, 1980-2015; 5 folders (Box 1)
    Administrative restriction until 2040.
  - Pamphlets/Newsletters, 1994-2017 (Box 1)
  - Reports, 2007-2011; 3 folders (Box 1)
    Administrative restriction until 2036.
  - Friedl, Ernestine, 1995-2008 (Box 1)
    Administrative restriction until 2033.
  - Women's Initative Duke University, 2003 (Box 1)
    Administrative restriction until 2028.